Southwest Folklore Center Field Recordings Collection 1943-ongoing
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Audio Recordings, 1943-ongoing; Series I
  - Blanche Hill, Interview with Blanche Hill, October 30, 1978; Tape contains interview with Hill about the song, "The Mormon Cowboy." She discusses the writing of the song which she claims to be about her husband, Ryan, by band leaders Brigham Young and Clarence Wills. Transcript available in 80-5/R.1.T. Collected by James Griffith. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 3 3/4 ips, 5 in. (Box 80.5, Folder R.1)
  - Frank Trammell, Rena Trammell, Jim and Mabel Bevell, Interviews, May 14, 1981; Tape contains interview with Rena Trammell of the Trammell-Bevell String Band and short interviews with other band members. Songs are performed by Frank and Rena Trammell, Jim and Mabel Bevell. Jim Bevell is Rena's brother and Mabel is his wife. Instruments include harmonica, guitar, mandolin and fiddle ... One morning in May -- Cattle call -- When its harvest time sweet Angeline -- Boil 'em cabbage down -- Precious jewel -- Soldier's joy -- Run nigger run -- Forever and ever -- Casey Jones -- Weeping willow (bury me beneath) -- Before I met you... Tape also includes a discussion about..."singin' to 'em at night in cow camps." Transcript available in 81.8/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith and Claire Rosenberg in Black Canyon City, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 81.8, Folder R.1)
  - Luther (Slim) Kite, Interview, May 15, 1981; Taped interview contains songs...Spanish fandango -- Spanish fandango (retake with tuning) -- In the valley of the moon -- La Cuña -- Redwing -- Mustang with wings -- Away on the mountains... Transcript available in 81.9/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 81.9, Folder R.1)
  - Luther (Slim) Kite, Interview, May 15, 1981; Tape includes stories, songs and poems... Ropin' Jane Russell -- Cowboy's dream -- Hell in Texas -- Persian Kitty -- [?] -- Cucumber story... Transcript available in 81.9/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 81.9, Folder R.2)
  - Dudley Whitlock, Interview, August 15, 1981; Tape includes brief interview and cowboy songs... Mother the queen of my heart -- Texas Ranger -- Custer's charge -- Tying the knots in the devil's tail -- The tenderfoot -- Zebra Dun -- Naponee... Transcript available in 81.14/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Miami, Arizona. sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 81.14, Folder R.1)
  - Bill Hensley, West Virginia banjo tunes, August 29, 1981; Tape includes interview with Hensley and West Virginia banjo music performed by him... Sugar Hill -- Wayne County girl (with words to "I've always been a rambler") -- Sailor's lament -- [Rueben] -- Wild Bill Jones -- Pretty Polly -- House carpenter -- John Hardy -- Cumberland Gap -- Single girl... Note on cover indicates that the banjo playing involves unusual tunings and playing techniques. Transcript available in 81.15/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 81.15, Folder R.1)
  - John Bradley, Cowboy and Grand Canyon songs, February 25, 1981; Tape contains interview with Bradley performing cowboy and Grand Canyon songs accompanied by Everett Brisendine... Vera, the Queen of the Canyon -- Story of the song, "Vera" -- Phantom Ranch dream -- Moonshine steer -- Zebra Dun -- All aboard for that Bright Angel Trail -- Eddie Steel -- Old apple tree... Transcript available in 81.18/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Cottonwood, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 81.18, Folder R.1)
  - Macedonian Baptist Church, Sing at Macedonian Baptist Church, July 27, 1980; Tapes contain program and songs from the Macedonian Baptist Church. Performing groups include: Macedonia Baptist Church Choir; Rising Star Baptist Church Choir; Ideal Baptist Church Choir; Pilgrim Rest Baptist Church Choir; Southside Baptist Church Choir; St. James Baptist Church Choir. The program continues on each tape... Song: Pass me not oh gentle Savior; Opening prayer: Reverend Hopkins; Congregational song: When all God's children; Macedonia Baptist Choir: I shall not be moved / While I'm on this Christian journey; Rising Star Baptist Choir: When Jesus comes / I have something in me; Ideal Baptist Choir: I'll rise again/Death can't keep me in the grave / Stop by; Pilgrim Rest Baptist Choir: Watching therefore/You shall wear [a] robe and crown / Every now and then / Altar Call; Congregation: He's sweet, I know / The more you give, the more he gives to you; Speaker: Rev. S.A. Dabner, moderator, Salt River Valley District Association; Southside Baptist Church Choir: I will never let go of his hand / It's another day's journey and I'm glad about it; St. James Baptist Church Choir: Just couldn't be contented / God never fails. Collected by James S. Griffith in Rillito, Arizona. 3 sound tape reels, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 81.19, Folder R.1, R.2, R.3)
  - Marion Maxwell, Interview and fiddle tunes, September 4, 1980; Tape contains interview and fiddle tunes performed by Maxwell accompanied by James S. Griffith on guitar... Ragtime Annie -- Maxwell schottische -- Put your little foot (1) -- Put your little foot (2) -- Escadilla waltz -- [original composition] -- Wedding march -- Mexican polka in A -- Over the waves -- Breakdown - Devils dream in A -- Turkey in the straw... Transcript available in 81.20/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Springerville, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 81.20, Folder R.1)
  - San Simeon Village School Group, Tohono O’Odham string music, December 20, 1981; Tape contains Tohono O’Odham string music cuadrilles, polkas, and pascola tunes performed at San Xavier Plaza Indian Craft Fair by Martin Antone (violin), Lopiz Angea (violin), James Angea (guitar) and Joe José (guitar) from San Simeon Village School... Cuadrille (Kuariya) -- Polka (Waila) -- Cuadrille -- Polka -- Pascola -- Pascola -- Pascola (incomplete)... Transcript available in 81.22/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in San Xavier Plaza, San Xavier Mission, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 81.22, Folder R.1)
  - Everett Brisendine, Cowboy stories and songs, January 19, 1982; Tape was recorded at Brisendine's house and includes songs and poems...Bronco stories: Bronco that landed on the car -- Chute and "Pitchfork" story -- Horse that fell over -- Horse in a right-hand spin -- My gun wouldn't shoot -- Rodeo in Arkansas... Windies: Old Flare and the Apaches -- Horse trader Sam King and the "loco stock" -- Horse traders "he ain't blind - he just don't give a damn"... Dude Wranglin': Hogs doubling to root -- Everett has got the slats on the horses -- Old Boy who dreamed he died and went to heaven -- Old Cowboys... Transcript available in 82.1/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Chino Valley, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.1, Folder R.1)
  - Everett Brisendine, Cowboy stories and songs, January 19, 1982; Tape 2 of 3 was recorded at Brisendine's house, Chino Valley, AZ., and includes poems and stories... Everett [Brisendine] says -- Cowboy dream -- This old house -- My gun wouldn't shoot -- Hackberry Slim Johnson story -- Bank Robbery in Clarksdale [by the] Nelson brothers, 1928 -- T-ranch working reminiscences -- Shipping cattle to California, 1928 -- Rex, King of the Wild Horses and a story about being accused of robbing the Clemenceau bank, 1932 -- Story about McCabe, AZ., 1936...Transcript available in 82.1/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Chino Valley, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.1, Folder R.2)
  - Everett Brisendine, Cowboy stories and songs, January 19, 1982; Tape 3 of 3 was recorded at Brisendine's house, Chino Valley, AZ., and includes the second part of the story about working in McCabe, AZ., in 1936. Transcript available in 82.1/R.3.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Chino Valley, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.1, Folder R.3)
  - Kenny Williams and Joe Sousa, Interview, January 18, 1982; Tape contains interviews with and cowboy stories by Williams and Sousa recorded at Sousa's house, Cactus Lane, Phoenix, AZ... Bee drive -- Open ledger -- The Castration of the Strawberry Roan -- The Salvation Army song -- I like my steak rare -- Story about asking for a raise, "Eat more" -- Trip to California -- Dude ranching stories -- Movie making -- Shipping cows story -- Burt Arnold's story, "I just brought your saddle back" (told by Joe Sousa) -- Collected by James S. Griffith in Phoenix, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.2, Folder R.1)
  - Hyrum Brakefield, Interview, December 11, 1980; Tape contains interview with and fiddle tunes by Brakefield accompanied by James S. Griffith on banjo... Lone star rag -- Three legged milk stool -- Tommy don't go -- Grey Eagle -- Mascot and Western Railroad... Transcript available in 82.5/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Phoenix, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.5, Folder R.1)
  - Marvin Bennett, Cowboy stories and songs, February 11, 1982; Tape 1 of 2 contains interview with and cowboy songs performed by Bennett. The interview discusses his life as well as five years he spent singing at the Grand Canyon in the 1930's. Songs include: Cowboy's dream -- Platoria, pride of the plains -- Old Pard/Dude Wrangler -- Lord I've never bothered you (the story of a cowboy getting bit by a tarantula while staying with a sheep herder). Transcript available in 82.7/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Mayer, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.7, Folder R.1)
  - Marvin Bennett, Cowboy stories and songs, February 11, 1982; Tape 2 of 2 contains a story told by Bennett, "Yavapai Pete" and a story about hearing the Indians pre-natally. Transcript available in 82.7/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Mayer, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.7, Folder R.2)
  - Jessie Cox, Fiddle tunes, May 5, 1982; Tape contains unaccompanied fiddle tunes by Jessie Cox... Animas Valley waltz -- Lonesome live oak -- I don't want to pick cotton, I want to run away -- Sally Gooden (announced as Arkansas traveller) -- Arkansas traveller -- Run nigger run -- Cowboy and the lady/One morning in May -- Bud Jones stomp -- Way out on the mountainside -- Arkansas traveller -- Eighth of January/Soldier's joy -- Put your little foot -- Turkey in the straw -- Rubber dolly -- Leather britches -- Over three hills... Transcript, including music and words to "Arimas Valley Waltz" is available in 82.13/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Geronimo's Castle Bar, Bowie, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.13, Folder R.1)
  - Clifford Head, Banjo and guitar music, January 13, 1977; Tape contains interview, banjo tunes and guitar music performed by Head of Bowie, AZ. Songs include: Bile them cabbage -- Cripple Creek -- Christmas time -- Nobody's business -- Bully of the town -- Old Joe Clark -- Red wing -- Green back -- Green corn -- Crocodile song -- Kicking mule -- Uncle Joe -- Arkansas traveller -- Waltz in D -- Rabbit in the meadow -- Playin' in the sand -- Before this time tomorrow -- Be in my fryin' pan -- Run mountain run -- Once I was goin' to see a girl -- 'Nother feller you too -- Only way I could get by him was to put on my long-tailed blue -- Run mountain run... Transcript available in 82.15/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Bowie, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 15 ips, 10 in. (Box 82.15, Folder R.1)
  - Clifford Head, Banjo music, May 6, 1982; This tape is blank. Material was re-recorded on tape 86.23/R.1. Collected by James S. Griffith in Geronimo's Castle Bar, Bowie, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.16, Folder R.1)
  - Clifford Head, Fiddle tunes, May 20, 1982; Tape contains fiddle tunes performed by Head. Tunes originated in various states as indicated by the state's name in parenthesis following the song title... Sally Ann/Great big taters (Alabama) -- Cackling hen (Alabama) -- Apple blossoms (Oklahoma) -- Apple blossoms -- Cherokee County waltz (Alabama) -- Climbin' up the golden stairs (Alabama) -- German (Lordsburg, New Mexico) -- Durang's hornpipe (Oklahoma) -- Leake County blues (Oklahoma) -- Lonesome blues (Oklahoma) -- Kelly waltz (Oklahoma)... Transcript available in 82.20/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Geronimo's Castle Bar, Bowie, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.20, Folder R.1)
  - Lois Thomas, Unaccompanied ballads, May 20, 1982; Tape contains unaccompanied ballads sung by Thomas of Bernice, Arizona... Falling Leaves -- Trail to Mexico -- Trail to Mexico(2) -- Only a gold miner killed in the mines/Gold miner's cabin -- Little Joe the wrangler -- Strawberry roan -- Zebra dun -- That's what the poor boy said -- When the work's all done this Fall -- Pictures from life's other side... Transcript available in 82.1/R.1.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Skeets' Tavern, Bowie, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips] 7 in. (Box 82.21, Folder R.1)
  - Gail Gardner, Interview, April 23, 1975; Dubbed tape 1 of 2 contains interview with Gardner of Prescott, Arizona, collected for the Library of Congress Bicentennial Record Project. Poems include:The Syerry Petes (The Sierry Petes) and the Moonshine Steer... These poems appeared on the Bicentennial Record. "Moonshine Steer" was used by James S. Griffith and Tucson radio station, KUAT, for the 1982 program,"Built on a Slim Foundation of Fact: A Look at Cowboy Humor" (See 81.5/C.1). Transcript available in 82.22/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith and Dick Spottswood. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.22, Folder R.1)
  - Gail Gardner, Interview, April 23, 1975; Dubbed tape 2 of 2 contains interview with Gardner of Prescott, Arizona, collected for the Library of Congress Bicentennial Record Project. Discussion about the early days of Rex Allen and Tom Mix... Poems include: The Dude wrangler and The Cowman's troubles... Transcript available in 82.22/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith and Dick Spottswood. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.22, Folder R.2)
  - Bill Hensley, Songs and banjo music, March, 1982; Dubbed tape contains songs with 5-string banjo accompaniment by Hensley of Tucson, AZ. Original tape sent to Keith Cunningham of Northern Arizona University for use on a phonodisc... Songs include: Roving gambler -- Mole in the ground -- Short Lu -- Pretty Polly -- Shady grove -- Shady grove(2) -- Wayne County girl -- Going 'round this world, baby mine -- Wild Bill Jones -- Fox chase -- Old Rueben -- Cumberland Gap -- Single girl... Transcript available in 82.23/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 82.23, Folder R.1)
  - Bill Hensley, Songs and banjo music, May 8, 1982; Dubbed tape 2 of 4 contains songs with 5-string banjo accompaniment by Hensley of Tucson, Arizona. Original tape was sent to Keith Cunningham of Northern Arizona University for use on a phonodisc. Songs include: John Henry -- John Henry(2) -- Poor Ellen Brown -- Short life and trouble -- Shortnin' bread -- Roving gambler -- Soldier's joy -- Old Joe Clark -- Ground hog -- If I had known before I counted (incomplete song)... Transcript available in 82.23/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 82.23, Folder R.2)
  - Bill Hensley, Songs and banjo music, May 30, 1982; Dubbed tape 3 of 4 contains songs with 5-string banjo accompaniment by Hensley of Tucson, Arizona. Original tape was sent to Keith Cunningham of Northern Arizona University for use on a phonodisc. Songs include: House carpenter -- House carpenter(2) -- Knoxville girl -- John declared he saw the train a'comin' -- Nobody's business -- Free little bird... Transcript available in 82.23/R.3.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 82.23, Folder R.3)
  - Bill Hensley, Songs and banjo music, May 15, 1982; Dubbed tape 4 of 4 contains songs with 5-string banjo accompaniment by Hensley of Tucson, Arizona. Original tape was sent to Keith Cunningham of Northern Arizona University for use on a phonodisc. Songs include: Wayne County girl -- Sailor's prayer -- Old Ruben -- Wild Bill Jones (Fox chase tuning) -- Sleepin' in the shade -- Sugar Hill -- John Hardy -- Turkey in the straw (with bows harp) -- Old Joe Clark (with bows harp) -- Old Ruben (with jews harp) -- Cumberland Gap (with jews harp)... Transcript available in 82.23/R.4.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 82.23, Folder R.4)
  - Dick Denny, Cowboy stories and songs, February 26, 1981; Dubbed tape of cassette 81.5/C.1. Transcript available in 81.5/C.1.T... Stories and songs include... Hop head/Bad Lee Brown -- Ropin' the frog -- Twinkle, twinkle little star (sung with Denny's daughters, Christine Denny, Donata Denny, and Marietta Denny) -- Platonia, pride of the plains -- Utah carrol -- Zebra dun -- Collected by James S. Griffith in Skull Valley, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.26, Folder R.1)
  - Dick Denny, Cowboy stories and songs, February 26, 1981; Dubbed tape of cassette 81.5/C.2. Interview with Denny and songs... I'm in love with a beautiful nurse -- I had but fifty cents -- Way up high in the Sierra Peaks -- Cowboy Bill is my name... Transcript available in 82.26/R.2.T. Collected by James S. Griffith in Skull Valley, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 82.26, Folder R.2)
  - Mrs. Lida Green, Songs, December 10, 1975; Tape contains unaccompanied songs performed by Green of Globe, Arizona. Songs include: Two little boys -- Eighth of January -- Across the wild moon -- Prisoner at the bar -- The Tie that binds -- Out upon the Western prairie... Transcript available in 82.36/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Globe, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 5 in. (Box 82.36, Folder R.1)
  - Mrs. Lida Green, Songs, December 10, 1975; Tape contains unaccompanied songs performed by Green of Globe, Arizona. Songs include: The Wedding bells -- Fair Fannie Moore -- The First astronaut (ballad about Alan Shepard of the U.S. space program)... Transcript available in 82.36/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Globe, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 5 in. (Box 82.36, Folder R.2)
  - Frank Trammell and Rena Trammell, Interview, June 26, 1976; From Acquisitions Inventory... Tape contains interview and songs by the Trammells, recorded in their motorhome, Payson, AZ. Frank plays harmonica; Rena sings and plays guitar... Soldier's joy -- One morning in May -- Run nigger run -- Bile them cabbage down -- Precious Lord take my hand -- Farther along... Transcript available in 82-40/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Payson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 5 in. (Box 82.40, Folder R.1)
  - Bill Garlinghouse, Songs, November 7, 1975; From Acquisitions Inventory... Tape 1 of 3 contains songs with harmonica (french harp) and guitar accompaniment performed by Garlinghouse of Wheatfield, AZ... Tape was made for the Smithsonian Institution's Festival of American Folklife, 1976. Cassette copies sent to the Smithsonian. Songs include: Wildwood flower -- Varsouvienne -- Wednesday night waltz -- Ragtime Annie -- Rye waltz -- Little Joe -- The Wrangler's sister, Nell -- Empty cot in the bunkhouse tonight -- Inside of old number nine... Transcript available in 82.41/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Wheatfield, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 5 in. (Box 82.41, Folder R.1)
  - Bill Garlinghouse, Songs, November 7, 1975; From Acquisitions Inventory... Tape 2 of 3 contains songs with harmonica and guitar accompaniment performed by Garlinghouse of Wheatfield, AZ... Tape was made for the Smithsonian Institution's Festival of American Folklife, 1976. Cassette copies sent to the Smithsonian. Songs include: Springerville -- Bonaparte's retreat -- Over the waves -- Soldier's joy -- Buffalo gals -- Jack of diamonds -- Golden slippers -- Under the double eagle -- Redoing -- Floyd Collins -- Little Mohee -- Jack and Joe -- Cowboy Jack -- Only a letter from home sweet home... Transcript available in 83-41/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Wheatfield, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 5 in. (Box 82.41, Folder R.2)
  - Bill Garlinghouse, Songs, November 7, 1975; From Acquisitions Inventory... Tape 3 of 3 contains interview and song, "My Juanita" performed by Garlinghouse of Wheatfield, AZ... Tape was made for the Smithsonian Institution's Festival of American Folklife, 1976. Cassette copies sent to the Smithsonian. Transcript available in 92.41/R.3.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Wheatfield, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 5 in. (Box 82.41, Folder R.3)
  - Mrs. Davis, Ballads, February 1, 1967; From Acquisitions Inventory... Tape includes unaccompanied ballads by Mrs. Davis and her daughter, Peggy Davis... Lady in the West -- Shanty boys -- Soldier and lady -- From Greenland's icy mountains... Transcript available in 82-42/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith. February 1, 1967; 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 5 in. (Box 82.42, Folder R.1)
  - Mrs. Davis, Ballads, February 1, 1967; From Acquisitions Inventory... Tape 2 of 2 includes unaccompanied ballads by Mrs. Davis and her daughter, Peggy Davis... Barbary Allen -- Little Onie... Transcript available in 82.42/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith. February 1, 1967; 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 5 in. (Box 82.42, Folder R.2)
  - Van Holyoak, Everett Brisendine, Marvin Bennett, Gail Gardner, and Dick Denny, Built on a slim foundation of fact: A look at cowboy humor, May 15, 1982; Tape contains radio program and interviews produced by James S. Griffith and Cephas Bowles. Complete transcript available in 83.6/C.1.T. Program aired July, 1982 and features stories, tall tales, and a song accompanied by Ed Smith and Dean Armstrong of Tucson, AZ. Collected by KUAT Readio in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 83.6, Folder R.1)
  - Bill Hensley, Old Time Mountain Music Concert, February 17, 1982; Tape 1 of 4 of the Old Time Mountain Music Concert co-sponsored by the University of Arizona's Southwest Folklore Center and the School of Music. Tape contains banjo tunes and songs performed by Bill Hensley... Wild Bill Jones -- Old Rueben -- Cumberland Gap -- Sailor's prayer -- Wayne County girl -- Poor Ellen Brown -- Short life and trouble... Between selections Hensley discusses how he learned to play the banjo. Transcript available in 83.13/R.1.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 83.13, Folder R.1)
  - Wade Mainer and Julie Mainer, Old Time Mountain Music Concert, February 17, 1982; Tape 2 of 4 of the Old Time Mountain Music Concert co-sponsored by the University of Arizona's Southwest Folklore Center and the School of Music. Tape contains banjo songs performed by Wade and Julie Mainer... Trickling water -- Watermelon on the vine -- Sweet fern -- Going to lay down my old banjo -- I'm blue and lonesome -- The old hen she cackles -- The Train that carried my girl from town -- Yonder she goes... Transcript available in 83.13/R.2.T.. Collected by James S. Griffith in Tucson, Arizona. 1 sound tape reel, analog, [7 1/2 ips], 7 in. (Box 83.13, Folder R.2)